## Lee Macaulay

#### Broadcast Journalist

Broadcast and multimedia journalist with 2+ years experience working in professional newsrooms at both the BBC and in commercial radio stations. Originally from Kendal, Cumbria, I've worked as a journalist across the North East, Cumbria and Lancashire.

#### Radio Reporter Radio Broadcaster Radio Producer **Digital Production** Web and Computer Misc Intermediate Intermediate Maste field recording adobe audition html/css linux/ubuntu live reporting news reading enps subediting tweetdeck full cle desk driving radioman reporter deployments mobile video shooting splice ios wordpress server admin quick edit pro bbc m newsgathering png bbc cps and vivo creative treatments

#### WORK EXPERIENCE (7)

#### Broadcast Journalist (Newsroom) at BBC Radio Cumbria

September 2015 - Current

http://www.bbc.co.uk/radiocumbria

Reporter, producer and newsreader on the BBC's local radio station for Cumbria which reaches around one in three adults a week.

- Produced Mike Zeller at Breakfast outside broadcast from Grasmere for the reopening of the A591 following damage from Storm Desmond.
- Reported for BBC Radio 4, BBC Radio Wales and BBC Tees during the 2015 Cumbrian floods.
- Regularly read bulletins, produce breakfast programmes, report live and write for news blog BBC Cumbria Live.
- Produced two separate week-long programme strands.

#### Multimedia News and Sport Reporter at CFM Radio

October 2014 - August 2015

http://www.cfmradio.co.uk

Gathered audio and wrote copy for hourly bulletins on Bauer Radio's commercial radio station broadcasting to North and West Cumbria. Updated social media and wrote news articles for the web.

- Reported from the Morecambe Bay inquiry report event for the Bauer City Network
- Reported from the 2015 General Election for the Bauer City Network

### Freelance Multimedia Reporter at Metro Radio and TFM

July 2014 - September 2014

http://www.metroradio.co.uk

Gathered audio and wrote copy for hourly bulletins on Bauer Radio's commercial radio stations for the North East. Updated social media and wrote news articles for the web.

#### Freelance Multimedia Reporter at Rock FM

May 2014 - June 2014

http://www.rockfm.co.uk

#### Work Experience at ITV Border

May 2014 - May 2014

http://www.itv.co.uk/border

- Produced and edited a package for weekend bulletins
- Wrote and cut video for breakfast bulletins

#### Radio Festival Radio at The Radio Academy

October 2013 - October 2013

https://www.radioacademy.org/

Worked with a team of young broadcasters to make radio from, and about, the UK radio industry's biggest event. Edited, co-produced and co-presented daily podcasts and produced a package about future user interfaces in radio.

## Casual Broadcast Assistant at BBC Radio Cumbria

April 2013 - June 2014

http://www.bbc.co.uk/radiocumbria

Provided on-air production and phone support for weekend and weekday programmes.

#### EDUCATION (3) -

# PGDip Broadcast Journalism at University of Central Lancashire 2013 - 2014

digital journalism media law public affairs

BA (Hons) Journalism, Film and Media at Cardiff University

#### GCSEs & A Levels Various Subjects at Kirkbie Kendal School

1999 - 2006

a level sociology  $\,$  a level business studies  $\,$  a level religious studies (philosophy & ethics)  $\,$  10.5 gcses (a\*-c)

#### AWARDS

Bronze, Best Journalistic Programming at Student Radio Awards

as part of the Xpress Radio News Team

Best Mainstream Show at Cardiff Student Media Awards 2007

Best News Reporter at Cardiff Student Media Awards

judged by Jon Snow, Channel 4 News

### INTERESTS —

 reading
 walking
 technology

 non-fiction
 margaret atwood
 novice hillwalker
 pebble smartwatch ios

 bryan-lee o'malley
 one wainwright summit
 xbox one